Guide to the The Inquiry Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records Regarding Administrative Matters, 1917-1919, undated; Series II
  - Progress Reports
    - [Progress Report] Letter from Sidney Mezes to Colonel House, 1918 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - [Progress Report] Letter from Isaiah Bowman to Colonel House, 1918 June 22 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Work in cooperation with Government bureaus.
    - [Progress Report] [copy] Scott, Woolsey, and David Hunter Miller, 1918 July (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Briefing material on international law. Enclosure: covering letter to Colonel House, 28 June 1918.
    - [Progress Report] Letter from Sidney Mezes to Colonel House, 1918 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Douglas Johnson Mission to England and France. Report, 1918 July 25 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Progress Report, Latin American Division, 1918 September 23 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      State of work; administrative note.
    - Research Committee. Report from Reference and Archive Division, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Minutes of Meetings
    - Research Committee: Minutes of meetings, 1918 August 9, 16, and 26 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Executive Committee: Minutes of meetings, 1918 August 12, 26 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Map Committee: Minutes of meetings, 1918 August 13-14 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Editorial Committee: Memoranda on the plan of reports, Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Personal and organizational
    - Personnel: Statements drawn for Draft Boards, 1918 Jan, Nov, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Report on The Inquiry: The Scope and Method, 1918 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Personnel: Miscellaneous bulletins and memoranda, 1918 March-December (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Inquiry at Peace Conference. Letter from Sidney Mezes to Colonel House, 1918 June 14 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Suggestions for men to attend conference. Enclosure: memorandum on treatment of "What Was Russia" at Conference.
    - Organization of Inquiry [chart], 1918 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous lists of books and articles collected by Inquiry library, Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "A Brief Account of the Origin and Development of The Inquiry," by Sidney Mezes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Personnel: Miscellaneous biographical notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Memorandum on "Topics and personnel for the Peace Conference" [Allyn Young and Isaiah Bowman to Colonel House], Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Research Plans
    - Austria-Hungary: Economic and Social Questions. Letter and Memoranda by Robert J. Kerner to Charles Seymour and Clive Day, 1918 February 16 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Preliminary list of projected Inquiry reports on economic questions, 1918 April 10-13 (?) (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Inquiry Reports. Memoranda on research plans for Russian economics, maps representing regional studies, 1918 June 11, October 8, November 6 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Research Committee: Letter from Isaiah Bowman to Colonel House [no enclosure], 1918 August 17 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Suggestion for formation of Research Committee.
    - Preliminary survey of types of research projects by Inquiry for Peace Conference, Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Format of Reports: Two memoranda on format of reports (1 p., 2 pp.), Undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - "Outline of the Geographical Study of the Problem Areas" (2 pp.), Undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Papers
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Reports and Studies, 1917-1920, undated; Series III
  Reports are arranged alphabetically under principal geographical or topical categories (e.g. "Austria-Hungary;" "Zionism"): these categories contain one or more entries, each entry comprising a single report.
  Some cross-referencing will be found -- primarily with regard to Reports dealing with more than one territorial area.*
  To avoid confusion (and a proliferation of entries) certain sets of statistical tables, etc., have been grouped together under single headings.
  Individual [folder] entries are arranged as follows: (1) the full title of the Report (when known), or a representative description (if the title page is missing); (2) author's name; (3) date of completion of Report (or of its reception at The Inquiry's headquarters); (4) total number of pages, including appendices. (Wherever needed, additional descriptive information has been provided in a note.)
  Unless otherwise noted, Reports are in typescript (ribbon or carbon copies).
  The list of Reports is supplemented by an Index of Authors (appended).
  * Material regarding the following countries can be found under Boundary Disputes:
  Argentina
  Bolivia
  Chile
  Colombia
  Ecuador
  Honduras
  Nicaragua
  Peru
  Uruguay
  Venezuela
  - Aaland
    - "A Memorandum on the Aland Question." By L. Milmore [American Legation, Stockholm.] 73 pp. and Maps. Photostats., Received 1918 July 29 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Includes a covering letter to William Phillips, 1918 June 29.
  - Abyssinia
    - "Abyssinia, A Report on the Present Commercial Status of the Country with Special Reference to the Possibilities for American Trade." By A. E. Southard [American Consulate, Aden, Arabia]. 143 pp., 1918 January 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Includes a covering letter to the Secretary of State, 1918 Jan 5.
  - Aden
    - "Report on Economic Changes in Aden District in Accordance with Department's Circular Number Two." By Arthur G. Watson [American Consulate, Aden, Arabia]. 17 pp., 1918 June 27 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Adriatic Ports
    - "Ports and Harbors of the East Adriatic Coast." [no author] 2 pp., Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Adriatic Question
    See: Italy, box 14, folder 195-199.
    See: Yugoslavia, box 24, folder 377-384.
    See: Dalmatia, box 10, folder 135-137.
  - Afganistan
    See: box 13, folder 177-189.
  - Africa
    See also: box 9A, folder 104-107.
    See also: box 21, folder 313.
    See also: box 16, folder 229.
    - "Notes on African Ethnography." By G. M. Wrigley. 11 pp. [and map], 1918 January 29 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "The German Colonies in Africa." By Wrigley Louis Beer. 81 pp., 1918 February 26 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "German Interests in Tropical Africa." By P. T. Moon. 6pp., Received 1918 June 24 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes covering note to Walter Lippmann, 1918 Jun 12.
    - "Islamism in Africa." By G. M. Wrigley. 7 pp. [map missing], Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "African Questions at the Peace Conference." By G. L. Beer [?]. 12 pp., Received 1918 February 11 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - "Tropical Africa." [no author] 79 pp., Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Title page and page 1 missing.
    - Africa, South.
      See: box 21, folder 312.
  - Albania
    - "Albania." By C. A. Chekrezi. 94 pp., Received 1918 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "Albania." By W. S. Monroe. 213 pp., Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Albania." [two reports ] By Fan S. Noli. 19 pp., Received 1918 April 3 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Education in Albania." By P. Monroe with O. B. Griffin. 332 pp., Received 1918 November 16 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "The Mirdites of Albania." By W. S. Monroe. 4 pp., 1918 October 4 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Southern Albania." [no author] 3 pp., Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Rough draft in manuscript marked "not used".
  - Algeria
    - "Economic Changes in Algeria Since the War." A. C. Frost [American Consul, Algiers]. 37 pp., 1918 June 20 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Alsace-Lorraine
    - "Alsace." [no author] 2 pp., Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "Alsace-Lorraine." By E. B. Krehbiel. 125 pp., Received 1918 March 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "Alsace-Lorraine." By E. B. Krehbiel [?] 110 pp., Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Title page missing.
    - "The Editorial on Alsace-Lorraine." By J. T. Shotwell. 4pp., 1918 January 30 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      Memoranandum to Sidney E. Mezes.
    - "German Opinion as to the Amount of Francophile Feeling in Alsace-Lorraine Since the War." By W. Notestein. 20 pp., Received 1918 October 28 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "The German Title to the Lorraine Iron Region." By J. H. Jacoby. [circa 110 pp. including appendices], Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "The Landtag of Alsace-Lorraine Since the War." By W. Notestein. 22 pp., Received 1918 November 12 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Alsace-Lorraine, Private Ownerships." By W. Notestein. 4 pp., Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Problems of Alsace-Lorraine." By C. H. Haskins. 133 pp., 1918 November 14 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "The Question of Alsace-Lorraine." [no author] 7 pp., Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Solution of Alsace-Lorraine Problem." By W. Notestein. 19 pp., Received 1918 October 26 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - "The Speech Boundary between French and German in Alsace-Lorraine and its Bearing on the National Affinities of the Territory." By Edward C. Armstrong. 20 pp., 1918 April 30 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      Map missing.
    - "Alsace-Lorraine, Statistical Report on Emigration and Immigration, 1871-1915." By Hetty Goldman. 52 pp., Received 1918 April 27 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      Photostats in Appendices.
    - "A Suggested Settlement of the Alsace-Lorraine Question." By John Storck. 1 p., 1918 January 18 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      Memorandum to Walter Lippman.
    - Alsace-Lorraine, Tentative Report. By W. Notestein and R. Updegraff. 21 pp., 1918 October 26 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      Based on clipping in New York Tribune, 1918 Oct 26, p. 2; received 1918 Oct 28.
    - "The Treatment of Alsace-Lorraine Since the War, July 1914 to October 1918." By W. Notestein. 69 pp., Received 1918 October 26 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - "Who's Who in Alsace-Lorraine, 1907-1917." By Rachel Updegraff. May 1918, revised in November. 28 pp., 1918 November (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Arab Problem
    See also: box 16, folder 232.
    See also:box 4, folder 5-10.
    - "The Arab Problem in Relation to Syria, Palestine and Mesopotamia." By Leon Dominian., 1918 April 15 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Arabia
    - "Arabia." By Leon Dominian. 38 pp., 1918 March 31 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - "Arabia." By C. C. Torrey. 69 pp., 1918 January 10 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      Pages 52, 55, 61, 62, and 63 missing.
  - Argentina
    - "Argentina, Outline Study of the Existing Conditions (Preliminary and Provisional) (Subject to Correction)." By G. M. McBride. 38 pp., 1918 June (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - "Report on the Patagonian Oil Fields." Campbell W. Hunter. 51 pp., 1920 April 20 (Box 6, Folder 38a)
    - "Important Economic Changes in Argentina during the War." By W. Henry Robertson. 23 pp., 1918 August 14 (Box 6, Folder 38a)
    - "Economic Changes in the Rosario District as related to the position of the district in the world's trade since the beginning of the War." By [A. L. ?] Bonney. 13 pp., 1918 August 12 (Box 6, Folder 38a)
  - Asia
    General note
    See also: box 9A, folder 108.
    - "Preliminary Memorandum to Accompany Map of Asia ." By Leon Dominian. 5 pp., 1918 January 31 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Asia Minor
    See:box 22-24, folder 326-371.
  - Assyrian Christians
    - "Report on the Assyrian Christians." By David Magie. 88 pp., 1918 August 24 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Australasia
    - "The Position of Australasia in Regard to the Peace Settlement." By P. W. Slosson. 42 pp., Received 1918 May 4 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      Bibliography missing.
  - Australia
    - "Report on Industrial Conditions in, and Trade with, Australia." [American Consulate, Sydney, Australia.] 31 pp., 1918 June 8 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Austria
    See: box 6-8, folder 43-71.
  - Austria-Hungary
    See also: box 36.
    See also: box 8, folder 94-96.
    See also: box 12, folder 163-170.
    See also: box 24, folder 377.
    See also: box 4, folder 4.
    - "Epitome of Boundaries in Austria-Hungary." [no author] 89 pp., Undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - "Austria-Hungary: Economic." By Clive Day. 66 pp., 1918 March 1 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - "Report on Economic Organization of Austria-Hungary." By Clive Day. 50 pp., 1918 February 1 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - "Historical Divisions in Austria-Hungary." By Charles Seymour. 5 pp., 1918 May 25 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - "Historical Divisions in Austria-Hungary, Explanatory Text to Map." By Charles Seymour. 5 pp., 1918 May 25 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - "Memorandum on the Form of Linguistic and Religious Statistics for Austria-Hungary." By Charles Seymour. 3 pp., Undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Memorandum on Method of Procedure of Boundary Study of Austria-Hungary. By Clive Day. 2 pp., 1919 January (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - "Report on Austria: Material Resources." By Charles Seymour. 19 pp., 1918 February 1 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - "Report on Austria: Population Studies." By Charles Seymour. Feb. 1, 1918.
      - Material requested for Feb. 1, 1918. [anon] 1p., Undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
        Memorandum addressed to Charles Seymour and Clive Day and 1 page notes in manuscript.
      - Introductory. 12 pp. (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Density of Population. 40 pp. (Box 6, Folder 51)
        1 statistical table in photostat; 1 statistical table in manuscript.
      - Distribution of Illiterates. 5 pp. (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Distribution of Religions. 47 pp. (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Racial Distribution. 77 pp. (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - General Appendix. [Section 6, # 13-20, Key map of Austria in sections showing names and boundaries of Politische Bezirke, boundaries of Gerichts Bezirke numbered with explanatory legend. photostats and Section 3, # 8-10. photostats] (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Research notes (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - "Distribution of Landed Property in Austria." By Charles Seymour. 15 pp., 1918 April 1 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - [Austria-Hungary: Ethnography] "General Criticism of the British Government Racial Contour Map of Austria-Hungary." By Robert J. Kerner and Charles Seymour. 9 pp., Received 1918 June 5 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      [Dictated by Robert J. Kerner.
    - "Austria-Hungary Federalized Within Existing Boundaries, Explanatory Text to Map." By Charles Seymour. 13 pp., 1918 May 25 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - "Galicia." By Clive Day. 48 pp., 1918 April 8 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - "Austria-Hungary. Memorandum on Structure of Government." By Robert J. Kerner (?) 33 pp., Received 1918 February 5 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      With manuscript annotations and corrigenda, p. 2 to p. 21. "Digest".
    - "Social and Economic Basis of Nationalism in Austria Statistical Study." By Charles Seymour. 232 pp., 1918 March (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - "Memorandum on the Political Effect of the Austrian, Russian and Buffer-State Solutions of the Polish Question upon the Economic Relations of Austria-Hungary with her Neighbors." By Robert J. Kerner. 27 pp., 1918 February 25 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - "Austria-Hungary: Polish Trialism." By Charles Seymour. 8 pp., 1918 May 25 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      Explanatory text to map.
    - [Austria-Hungary] "Problems." [no author] 16 pp., Undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
      First draft; precis.
    - "Digest of Memorandum on Racial Participation in the Government of Austria-Hungary." By Robert J. Kerner., Received 1918 February 9 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - "Program of Topics Suggested by Collaborators for Research in Austria-Hungary to November 1, 1918." By Clive Day, Charles Seymour, Robert J. Kerner. 17 pp., 1918 July 25 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      Includes memorandum on program, 1918 Aug 1, 1 page.
    - "Austrian School Laws and Administration Regulations Concerning Private Schools, Teaching Orders, Teaching of Foreign Languages, Educational Privileges and Subject Peoples, and in General the Use of Schools for Nationalistic Ends." By P. Monroe, assisted by I. L. Kandel. 143 pp., Undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - "The Slavs of Austria-Hungary." By A. H. Putney. 236 pp., 1918 May 9 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - "Slav Aspiriations in Austria-Hungary: The Corridor Statistical Study." By Charles Seymour. 32 pp., 1918 April 1 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - "Austria-Hungary: Territorial Solutions of the Jugo-Slav Problem." [no author] 4 pp., Undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - "Memorandum on Solutions of the Austro-Hungarian Question." By Robert J. Kerner. 45 pp., Received 1918 February 8 (Box 7, Folder 67)
      With manuscript notes and miscellaneous corrigenda.
    - "Austro-Italian Boundary Dispute: Trentino and Trieste." By A. P. Evans. 23 pp., 1918 February 1 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - "Austro-Italian Boundary Dispute: Trentino and Trieste." By A. P. Evans. 77 pp., Undated (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - "The Strategic Character of the Austro-Italian Frontier." By E. C. Semple. 58 pp., 1918 March 13 (Box 7, Folder 70)
      With a precis, 3 pp., 1918 Apr.
    - "The Rumanians of Hungary, Districts with a Rumanian Majority Statistical Study." By Charles Seymour. 34 pp., 1918 April 1 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Azores
    - "Important Economic Changes in District, since the beginning of the War, especially those likely to alter its position in the world's market." By John Q. Wood. 6 pp., 1918 June 20 (Box 8, Folder 71a)
  - Balkans
    See also: box 4-5, folder 11-16.
    See also: box 10, folder 138-139.
    See also: box 15, folder 221-224.
    See also: box 16, folder 237.
    See also: box 20, folder 290-293.
    See also: box 21, folder 305.
    See also:box 24, folder 377-384.
    - "Preliminary Report on the Balkan Boundaries." By Clive Day. 26 pp., Undated (Box 8, Folder 72)
      Preliminary draft and two revisions.
    - "Boundaries in the Balkans." By Clive Day. 52 pp., Undated (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - "Catalogue of the Ethnographic Maps of the Balkans." By W. S. Monroe. 38 pp., 1918 June 27 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - [Balkan Foreign Relations] [3 reports:]
      - "Acquisition of Balkan States at the End of the Second Balkan War." By W. S. Monroe. 8 pp., Received 1918 March 12 (Box 8, Folder 75)
      - "American Influence in the Balkans." By W. S. Monroe. 6 pp., Undated (Box 8, Folder 75)
      - "Resume of the Balkan Treaties." By W. S. Monroe. 52 pp., Received 1918 May 20 (Box 8, Folder 75)
        Maps - printed.
    - "Forests of the Balkan Peninsula." By W. S. Monroe. 18 pp., 1918 nov 8 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - "Memorandum on the Balkan Question." By J. C. White. 47 pp., Undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
      With a covering letter to Colonel House, 1918 Jan 15.
    - "Minerals of the Balkan Peninsula." By W. S. Monroe. 17 pp., 1918 November 12 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - "Balkan Peninsula." By W. S. Monroe. 104 pp., 1918 March 1 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - "Balkan Peninsula, Religious Toleration: Effect of the Stipulation of the Treaty of Berlin in Serbia, Montenegro, and Rumania that Religion Should Be Free." By W. S. Monroe. 15 pp., 1918 March 25 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - [Balkans] Plans for a Series of Reports on Balkan Areas: Albania, Macedonia, Thrace, Dobrudja, Serbia, and Montenegro. [no author] 7 pp., Undated (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Baltic Provinces
    See also: box 15, folder 212.
    See also: box 15, folder 213-219.
    - "The Baltic Provinces: General Article." By F. A. Golder. Jan. 15, 1918. 97 pp. (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - "The People of the Baltic Provinces and Lithuania." [no author] n.d. 21 pp. (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - "The Baltic Provinces: Latvia and United Esthonia." By S. B. Fay. Nov 27, 1918. 65 pp. (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Basutos
    - "The Native Council of the Basutos." [no author] 4 pp., Received 1918 June 15 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Belgian Congo
    - "The Belgian Congo During the War." By E.V. Le Plae. 22 pp., Undated (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Belgium
    - "Outline of Report on Belgium." By C. H. Haskins. 2 pp., 1918 July 29 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - "Belgian Economic Conditions (References to Articles in Periodicals Which May Be of Use to Investigators of Some Aspects of the Economic Interests of Belgium)." By Clive Day. 3 pp., 1918 May 14 (Box 8, Folder 88)
      To Andrew Keogh; with covering letter to C. H. Haskins, 1918 May 8. (incomplete)
    - "Belgium: Education in Belgium School Laws." [no author] 9 pp., Undated (Box 8, Folder 89)
      Incomplete?
    - "Belgium: Political Parties and Elections." By E. H. Krehbiel. 10 pp., Received 1918 March 19 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - "Rehabilitation of Belgium." By J. P. Chamberlain. 15 pp., Undated (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Berlin Congress
    - "The Berlin Congress." By H. F. Munro. 74 pp., 1918 October 14 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Bessarabia
    - "Bessarabia." By W. H. Reed. 26 pp. [with map], 1918 March 11 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Bohemia
    - "Principles Assumed in Locating Boundaries. Boundaries for Bohemia West of the Elbe." By Mark Jefferson. 2 pp., 1918 September 16 (Box 8, Folder 94)
      2-part memorandum.
    - "Czech Minorities in Bohemia: A Statistical Survey." By Robert J. Kerner. 123 pp., 1918 November 1 (Box 8, Folder 95)
      Manuscript note re: map.
    - "Bohemia: Miscellaneous Statistical Tables on Trade and Production." By Clive Day., Received 1918 June 13 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Bolivia
    - "Intimate Description of Oriental Bolivia." [no author] 11 pp., Undated (Box 9, Folder 97)
      With map in photostat appended.
    - "Proposed Railways in Eastern and Northern Bolivia." [no author] 5 pp. [with map], Undated (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - "Circular of the Latin American Division: Bolivian Tin." Bureau of Foreign and Domesic Commerce, Department of Commerce. 5 pp., 1918 July 27 (Box 9, Folder 98A)
  - Boundary Disputes
    - "Argentina-Uruguay: Jurisdiction of the Rio de la Plata." [no author] 91 pp., Undated (Box 9, Folder 98B)
    - Chile-Bolivia boundary dispute (Box 9, Folder 98C)
    - "Chile-Peru-Bolivia: The Tacna-Arica Dispute." [No author] 128 pp., Undated (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Chile-Peru-Bolivia: Tacna-Arica Dispute (Box 9, Folder 98E)
    - Colombia-Brazil (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - "The Colombia-Ecuador Boundary." [no author] 6 pp., Undated (Box 9, Folder 98G)
    - "The Colombia-Panama Frontier." [no author] 9 pp., Undated (Box 9, Folder 98H)
    - "Colombia-Peru Boundary." [no author] 38 pp., Undated (Box 9, Folder 98I)
    - "Colombia-Venezuela Boundary." [no author] 45 pp., Undated (Box 9, Folder 98J)
    - Honduras and Nicaragua (Box 9, Folder 98K)
    - "Peru-Bolivia Boundary." [no author] 39 pp., Undated (Box 9, Folder 98L)
    - South America (Box 9, Folder 98M)
  - Brazil
    - "Intimate Descriptions: State of Matto Grasso, Central Brazil." [no author], Undated (Box 9A, Folder 99)
      Map in photostat appended.
    - "Outline Study of the Existing Conditions: Brazil." [no author] 34 pp., 1918 (Box 9A, Folder 99a)
    - "Southern Brazil." By F. B. Morris. 22 pp., 1918 September (Box 9A, Folder 100)
    - Brazil economic conditions (Box 9A, Folder 100a)
    - "Notes on the Salesian Missions and the Bororro Indians." By George B. Holderer. 17 pp., 1913 October (Box 9A, Folder 100b)
  - Brussels Sugar Convention
    - "Brussels Sugar Convention." By M. G. Marsh. 52 pp., Received 1918 September 11 (Box 9A, Folder 101)
  - Bukovina
    See: box 17-19, folder 252-283.
  - Burma
  - Caribbean
    - "Interests of the United States in the Caribbean: Physical and Commercial Outline." [no author] 130 pp., Undated (Box 9A, Folder 101a)
  - Catholic Church
    - "Influence of the Catholic Church in Argentina and Chile." [no author] 18 pp., Undated (Box 9A, Folder 101b)
  - Caucasus
    - "The Caucasus." By A. I. Andrews. 154 pp., Undated (Box 9A, Folder 102)
    - "Caucasus: Commerce and Trade Routes." By L. H. Gray. 8 pp., 1918 March 5 (Box 9A, Folder 103)
  - Central Africa
    - "The Climate of Central Africa in Relation to the Health of Europeans." By G. M. Wrigley. 5 pp., Undated (Box 9A, Folder 104)
    - "Central Africa: The Economic Aspects of the Problem." By G. L. Beer. 135 pp., 1918 May 2 (Box 9A, Folder 105)
    - "Central Africa As a Field for European Colonization." By G. M. Wrigley. 14 pp., 1918 January 31 (Box 9A, Folder 106)